var history_ancient_questions = [
  {
    "no": 1,
    "question": "Who was the founder of the Maurya Empire?",
    "option_1": "Chandragupta Maurya",
    "option_2": "Ashoka",
    "option_3": "Bindusara",
    "option_4": "Chandragupta I",
    "correct_option": 1
  },
  {
    "no": 2,
    "question": "Which ancient Indian script is considered the precursor of modern Indian scripts like Devanagari?",
    "option_1": "Brahmi",
    "option_2": "Kharosthi",
    "option_3": "Gupta",
    "option_4": "Pali",
    "correct_option": 1
  },
  {
    "no": 3,
    "question": "The concept of 'Ahimsa' (non-violence) was popularized by which ancient Indian leader?",
    "option_1": "Ashoka",
    "option_2": "Kanishka",
    "option_3": "Chandragupta Maurya",
    "option_4": "Harsha",
    "correct_option": 1
  },
  {
    "no": 4,
    "question": "Which ancient Indian ruler is known for his rock-cut architecture at sites like Ajanta and Ellora?",
    "option_1": "Chandragupta Maurya",
    "option_2": "Kanishka",
    "option_3": "Harsha",
    "option_4": "Chandragupta II",
    "correct_option": 4
  },
  {
    "no": 5,
    "question": "The ancient university of Nalanda was a center of learning in which present-day Indian state?",
    "option_1": "Bihar",
    "option_2": "Uttar Pradesh",
    "option_3": "Madhya Pradesh",
    "option_4": "West Bengal",
    "correct_option": 1
  },
  {
    "no": 6,
    "question": "Which ancient Indian text is a compilation of hymns dedicated to various Vedic gods and goddesses?",
    "option_1": "Ramayana",
    "option_2": "Mahabharata",
    "option_3": "Rigveda",
    "option_4": "Bhagavad Gita",
    "correct_option": 3
  },
  {
    "no": 7,
    "question": "The capital city of the Chola Empire was located in present-day:",
    "option_1": "Chennai",
    "option_2": "Madurai",
    "option_3": "Tanjore",
    "option_4": "Hyderabad",
    "correct_option": 3
  },
  {
    "no": 8,
    "question": "Who among the following was NOT a ruler of the Gupta Empire?",
    "option_1": "Chandragupta I",
    "option_2": "Samudragupta",
    "option_3": "Kumaragupta",
    "option_4": "Harshavardhana",
    "correct_option": 4
  },
  {
    "no": 9,
    "question": "The Iron Pillar, located in Delhi, bears an inscription attributed to which ancient Indian ruler?",
    "option_1": "Chandragupta Maurya",
    "option_2": "Ashoka",
    "option_3": "Chandragupta II",
    "option_4": "Samudragupta",
    "correct_option": 3
  },
  {
    "no": 10,
    "question": "Which ancient Indian ruler is known for his propagation of Buddhism across Asia?",
    "option_1": "Kanishka",
    "option_2": "Harsha",
    "option_3": "Chandragupta Maurya",
    "option_4": "Samudragupta",
    "correct_option": 1
  }
];